Unfilial son
Предатель
You unfilial son
Ты предатель
I will absolutely not abdicate to you
Я ни за что не отрекусь в твою пользу
Father
Отец
Don't force your son
Не вынуждайте меня
You withdraw for now
Отойди
Today
Сегодня
I can still spare you
я ещё готов тебя пощадить
Then don't blame your son
Тогда не вините меня
For all under heaven
Ради народа и мира в стране
For the people's peace
ради мира и спокойствия народа
I
Я
Sikong Sheng
Сыкун Шэн
Am willing to be an unfilial descendant
готов стать недостойным сыном
The 22nd year of Longwu
22й год Луньвэя
The court announced to all
Двор официально объявил
Emperor Sikong Yao died of serious illness
император Сыкун Яо скоропостижно скончался от тяжёлой болезни
Crown Prince Sikong Sheng announced his succession
Престол занял наследный принц Сыкун Шэн
But not long after
Однако вскоре
Second Prince Sikong Xu raised troops, claiming Sikong Sheng forced the late emperor's death
второй принц Сыкун Сюй обвинил Сыкун Шэна в убийстве отца ради трона
And usurped the throne
и поднял мятеж
Xuan Kingdom fell into civil war again
Государство Сюань вновь погрузилось в хаос
The same year
В том же году
Shilang took advantage of the Sikong royal family's internal strife
Ши Лан воспользовался междуусобной войной в императорской семье
Marched south
и повёл армию на юг